<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
>

<channel>
<title>Around the Corner</title>
<atom:link href="https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<link>https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation</link>
<description>Innovation in the Business of Government: A GSA Blog</description>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 20:04:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.7.3</generator>
<item>
<title>GSA celebrates National Cyber Security Awareness month</title>
<link>https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/2016/10/20/gsa-celebrates-national-cyber-security-awareness-month/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 18:50:06 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Shive]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Security]]></category>

<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/?p=1172</guid>
<description><![CDATA[(Note: This post also appears at the GSA Blog) This October, the General Services Administration (GSA) joins the nation in celebrating the 13th annual National Cyber Security Awareness Month, a [&#8230;]]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1174" style="width: 637px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/10/cybersecurity-2-848x400.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1174" src="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/10/cybersecurity-2-848x400-300x142.jpg" alt="Cyber security concept on virtual screen with a consultant doing presentation in the background" width="627" height="297" srcset="https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/10/cybersecurity-2-848x400-300x142.jpg 300w, https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/10/cybersecurity-2-848x400-768x362.jpg 768w, https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/10/cybersecurity-2-848x400.jpg 848w" sizes="(max-width: 627px) 100vw, 627px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Cyber security concept on virtual screen with a consultant doing presentation in the background</p></div>
<p>(Note: This post also appears at the <a href="https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/gsablog/2016/10/20/gsa-celebrates-national-cyber-security-awareness-month/">GSA Blog</a>)</p>
<p>This October, the General Services Administration (GSA) joins the nation in celebrating the 13th annual National Cyber Security Awareness Month, a nationwide effort to educate and engage government and private sector stakeholders and the American public on cybersecurity issues through a variety of outreach and events held across the country.</p>
<p>The internet touches almost all aspects of everyone’s daily life. We shop, bank, connect with loved ones, pay our bills, and manage our medical records online. Our increased connectivity brings extraordinary benefits but also brings increased risks to our nation’s economic and national security. Recent large scale cyber attacks have not only exposed the personal information of millions of Americans but also compromised sensitive information and intellectual property.</p>
<p>National Cyber Security Awareness Month is a collaborative effort between the private and public sector to ensure all Americans have the tools and resources they need to stay safe online. Through events and outreach during the month, National Cyber Security Awareness Month raises awareness about cybersecurity and enlists all Americans to help make the Internet safer and more secure.</p>
<p>This month, we put cybersecurity at the forefront of the national dialogue and renew our commitment to enhancing the security of our nation while preserving a culture that fosters innovation and growth in technology. Cybersecurity is our shared responsibility – we all play a role in making the Internet safer and more secure.</p>
<p>Throughout National Cyber Security Awareness Month, we urge every American to help create a safer and more secure cyber environment by taking steps to keep themselves, their identities, and their information safe online. This includes simple things everyone can do every day, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Set strong passwords with 8 characters or more and a combination of upper and lower case letters.</li>
<li>Lock Down Your Login by enabling strong authentication options on your sensitive accounts, like for banking and email (https://www.lockdownyourlogin.com).</li>
<li>Keep your operating system, browser, and other critical software optimized and secure by installing updates.</li>
<li>Maintain an open dialogue with your family, friends, and community about Internet safety.</li>
<li>Limit the amount of personal information you post online, and use privacy settings for your apps and social media websites; and</li>
<li>Be cautious about what you receive or read online; if it sounds too good to be true, it probably is.</li>
</ul>
<p>GSA supports the Department of Homeland Security and our Federal partners by proactively advancing cybersecurity awareness through outreach and information sharing. Since the President’s proclamation in 2004, National Cyber Security Awareness Month has been formally recognized by Congress, federal, state, and local governments, and leaders from industry and academia. This united effort is essential to creating a safer, more resilient cyberspace that remains a source of tremendous opportunity and growth for years to come.</p>
<p>For more information on National Cyber Security Awareness Month 2016, please visit ww.dhs.gov/national-cyber-security-awareness-month</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Earth Day Hackathon Helps the Government Go Green</title>
<link>https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/2016/04/25/earth-day-hackathon-helps-the-government-go-green/</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 20:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Shive]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Leadership]]></category>

<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/?p=1140</guid>
<description><![CDATA[(Note: This post also appears at the GSA Blog.) Since taking office, President Obama has made creating a more sustainable federal government one of his most important priorities. As the [&#8230;]]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/04/Earth-Day-Hackathon-1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-1142"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1142" src="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/04/Earth-Day-Hackathon-1.jpg" alt="Earth-Day-Hackathon-1" width="640" height="365" srcset="https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/04/Earth-Day-Hackathon-1.jpg 640w, https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/04/Earth-Day-Hackathon-1-300x171.jpg 300w, https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/04/Earth-Day-Hackathon-1-195x110.jpg 195w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>(<strong>Note:</strong> This post also appears at <a href="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/gsablog/2016/04/25/earth-day-hackathon-helps-the-government-go-green/" target="_blank">the GSA Blog</a>.)</p>
<p>Since taking office, President Obama has made creating a more sustainable federal government one of his most important priorities. As the government’s leading supplier of utilities, buildings, vehicles and technology, GSA also has unique opportunities to protect our environment.</p>
<p>That is why, on Earth Day, GSA hosted a Government-wide Earth Day Hackathon. Taking place in GSA’s headquarters in Washington, DC, the event brought together 49 industry professionals, students, and government employees to find new, more efficient solutions to making a greener federal government. Participating agencies included the U.S. General Service Administration, White House Council on Environmental Quality, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, National Institute of Standards and Technology, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the U.S. Department of Agriculture’s Forest Service.</p>
<p>Four participating teams were awarded prizes. Teams CGI Digital and ICF won for building an automated software code generator and developing improved data visualizations associated with climate change indicator data for the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. Team CVP won for developing a new web application for the National Institute of Standards and Technology that allows for selection and comparison of building products’ economic and environmental performance based on the user’s needs and preferences.  And team Smokey and the Bandits, from ICF, won for developing methods to present and compare performance on energy and water use in U.S. Department of Agriculture Forest Service facilities. All within the six hour window of the hackathon.</p>
<p>The winning teams received $3,750 in cash prizes. The data sets and more information on each project can be found at<a href="http://open.gsa.gov/EarthDayHackathon/">http://open.gsa.gov/EarthDayHackathon/</a>.</p>
<p>Hackathons support <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/open">open government</a>; encouraging innovation and collaboration between government agencies and the citizens we serve. This improves how government operates, injects innovation into government and facilitates transformation across agency boundaries. This is of great benefit to all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>Federal Workforce On Duty During Winter Storm Jonas</title>
<link>https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/2016/01/28/federal-workforce-on-duty-during-winter-storm-jonas/</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 17:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Shive]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[IT Investments]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Mobility]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Productivity]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Science & Technology]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Workforce]]></category>

<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/?p=1128</guid>
<description><![CDATA[(Note: This blog post also appears at The GSA Blog.) Last week Winter Storm Jonas pummeled the East Coast of the United States, leaving as much as 30 inches of [&#8230;]]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/01/Capitol-Under-the-Snow.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-1130"><img class="size-full wp-image-1130" src="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/01/Capitol-Under-the-Snow.jpg" alt="U.S. Capitol after morning snowstorm" width="518" height="295" srcset="https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/01/Capitol-Under-the-Snow.jpg 518w, https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/01/Capitol-Under-the-Snow-300x171.jpg 300w, https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/01/Capitol-Under-the-Snow-195x110.jpg 195w" sizes="(max-width: 518px) 100vw, 518px" /></a></p>
<p>(Note: This blog post also appears at <a href="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/gsablog/2016/01/28/federal-workforce-on-duty-during-winter-storm-jonas/">The GSA Blog</a>.)</p>
<p>Last week Winter Storm Jonas pummeled the East Coast of the United States, leaving as much as 30 inches of snow across the region. Despite federal buildings being closed due to impassable roads and suspended mass transit, U.S. General Service Administration (GSA) employees were able to carry out the agency’s mission using IT tools for telework.</p>
<p>In the Northeast and Caribbean Region, preparations began on Thursday when the region directed all employees in the impacted area to be ready to telework on Monday.Property managers prepped their buildings and ensured all snow removal equipment was ready to go. When Jonas did arrive it was much worse than predicted, instead of 6 to 12 inches of snow, the New York City Metro Area received 18 to 34 inches of snow.</p>
<p>Most GSA employees who could not make it to their offices used a variety of methods to work from home or other remote locations. Our data shows there are more than 3,800 employees in the DC area and approximately 3,600 were eligible to telework during the storm. The agency had the right infrastructure and technology support in place to be able to scale up to increased demand.</p>
<p>“Our GSA telework policy provides employees the flexibility to meet the needs of our customers from anywhere, while providing the benefit of increased work life balance,” noted Antonia T. Harris, GSA’s Chief Human Capital Officer. “It is great to see that during times of extreme weather or government closure, our workforce is still able to carry out our important mission for the American people.”</p>
<p>GSA’s Virtual Private Network (VPN), which provides a secure connection from a GSA-furnished computer or mobile device to the GSA network, experienced a three-fold increase in typical demand. Citrix, which allows remote access to GSA business applications and data which are only available on the GSA network, saw a 50 percent increase over the average number of applications launched per day. And, finally, MyView, which provides employees with a full virtual GSA Windows desktop experience, had higher-than-average use as employees used personal machines or mobile devices to access the GSA network.</p>
<p>Jonas isn’t the first storm to impact the federal government nor will it be the last. The <a href="http://www.gsa.gov/portal/category/21404">Chief Information Officer’s</a> office is focused on ensuring our networks can handle increased utilization during high demand periods, and that it allows employees access to the right tools with minimal disruption to their daily routine. Enabling a telework-ready environment is an inherent part of how we work at GSA and we’re proud that it enabled GSA to continue serving the American public during Winter Storm Jonas.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Salesforce Services BPA Ordering Guide Is Here!</title>
<link>https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/2016/01/20/the-salesforce-services-bpa-ordering-guide-is-here/</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 18:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Shive]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Acquisition]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Cloud Computing]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Enterprise Architecture]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[IT Investments]]></category>

<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/?p=1118</guid>
<description><![CDATA[(NOTE: This blog post is also posted at The GSA Blog.) On December 21st, GSA announced the award of the Salesforce Implementation, Integration, and Support Services (SIISS) BPA. Developed to [&#8230;]]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/01/Were-open-518x295.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-1120"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1120" src="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/01/Were-open-518x295.jpg" alt="Come in! We're Open!" width="518" height="295" srcset="https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/01/Were-open-518x295.jpg 518w, https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/01/Were-open-518x295-300x171.jpg 300w, https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2016/01/Were-open-518x295-195x110.jpg 195w" sizes="(max-width: 518px) 100vw, 518px" /></a></p>
<p>(NOTE: This blog post is also posted at <a href="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/gsablog/2016/01/20/the-salesforce-services-bpa-ordering-guide-is-here/">The GSA Blog</a>.)</p>
<p>On December 21st, <a href="http://www.gsa.gov/portal/content/121238">GSA announced</a> the award of the <a href="http://www.gsa.gov/portal/content/120966">Salesforce Implementation, Integration, and Support Services (SIISS) BPA</a>. Developed to centralize and streamline $503 million in IT Schedule 70 awards over five years, the BPA aims to bring all Salesforce-related professional services, from development to implementation, under one acquisition vehicle. With today’s release of the <a href="http://www.gsa.gov/portal/mediaId/122198/fileName/SIISSOrderingGuide11316.action">ordering guide</a>, GSA takes a critical step in helping make government more efficient and effective; reducing duplication, saving money, and sharing resources.</p>
<p><b>Moving Beyond the Technology</b></p>
<p>Annual federal spending on cloud computing is already in the billions  and is expected to potentially triple by 2020. As agencies increase  their use of cloud-based IT , the demand for cloud services will continue to expand. In order to meet the increasing demands and expectations of federal agencies, whose mission is to provide services to the  American taxpayers, it is critical that the government comes together as one to identify our common needs and maintain  the highest levels of quality when it comes to the the products and services we purchase to meet those needs. The SIISS BPA is a great step forward in meeting that goal.</p>
<p>With that expansion in mind, GSA’s Office of the CIO (GSA IT) partnered with the Federal Acquisition Service’s Integrated Technology Services and the Federal Salesforce Community of Excellence  (previously known as the Interagency Cloud Working Group)  to develop this first-of-its-kind BPA, which provides agencies quicker, faster, and cheaper access to high-quality, cost-effective services for Salesforce, one of the industry-leading Software-as-a-Service cloud providers. In addition to quality improvements, the BPA offers the opportunity for individual agencies to develop Salesforce applications with a consistent development and design approach, improving interoperability, reuse, and shareability of code across the government. GSA IT wants to take the lead in establishing a “build once, use many times” philosophy of IT development to maximize value across the federal government.</p>
<p>With so many common repeatable agency support functions and processes, our goal is for agencies to stop reinventing the wheel every time they have a Salesforce-based IT need. Applications developed under this BPA can be shared in a common repository called <a href="http://labs.gsa.gov/">GSA Labs</a>.  GSA Labs is an open government community for exchange of Salesforce applications and code hosted by the General Services Administration. As Anne Rung, the U.S. Chief Acquisition Officer stated in her recent <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2015/12/21/building-progress-improving-way-government-buys-it">blog</a> “Agencies can potentially save between 50 and 80 percent on application development costs by using the code and configuration hosted on GSA Labs.  For example, if an application costs $500k to build from scratch, agencies could save between $250k and $400k by leveraging existing applications or code snippets shared on GSA Labs”.</p>
<p>This BPA is another great example of how collaboration and integrating cross-agency requirements creates a better solution for everyone. Agencies can save time and money through this BPA while being assured this contract incorporates their agency’s needs for trusted and qualified integration companies. The rigorous evaluation standards, created in conjunction with Traci Walker (US Digital Services) and Mark Naggar (HHS OCIO), required vendors to demonstrate their ability to deliver specific technology expertise (in this case Salesforce) using an Agile methodology. This source selection strategy was designed to be used as a repeatable framework making future acquisitions for services faster and more efficient.</p>
<p><b>What’s Next?  </b></p>
<p>Today, we are releasing the <a href="http://www.gsa.gov/portal/mediaId/122198/fileName/SIISSOrderingGuide11316.action">SIISS Ordering Guide</a> so that agencies can start driving their Salesforce services procurements to this BPA. We encourage agencies to use the existing information provided through  <a href="http://labs.gsa.gov/">GSA Labs</a>, <a href="https://playbook.cio.gov/">the Digital Service Playbook</a>, and the <a href="https://playbook.cio.gov/techfar/">TechFAR</a> to utilize best practices, collaborate with others, and develop requirements faster and better than ever before. Also, you can share your success stories via the GSA Labs exchange.</p>
<p>This new contract will make the purchase of services to support the Salesforce platform much easier. GSA has long been a believer in the transformational power of the cloud and its ability to drive down costs for government. This BPA, with its focus on technical standards, reuse, and conduit for government application sharing, will continue to grow the power and scope of that transformation.</p>
<p>Stay tuned for future announcements and a behind-the-scenes view of the history and evolution of the Salesforce Services BPA at the SIISS BPA <a href="http://www.gsa.gov/portal/content/120966">website</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item>
<item>
<title>GSA Leadership Named to 2015 FedScoop 50</title>
<link>https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/2015/11/20/gsa-leadership-named-to-2015-fedscoop-50/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 20:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Shive]]></dc:creator>
<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Leadership]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Management and Operations]]></category>
<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/?p=1106</guid>
<description><![CDATA[(Note: This blog post also appears at The GSA Blog.) The federal technology community is taking notice of GSA’s drive to use technology to transform government as evident by awards [&#8230;]]]></description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2015/11/FedScoop50-484x220.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1108" src="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2015/11/FedScoop50-484x220-300x136.jpg" alt="GSA Administrator Denise Turner Roth, OCSIT Associate Administrator Phaedra Chrousos, Gwynne Kostin, Director of the OCSIT Digital Services Innovation Center, and GSA CIO David Shive" width="300" height="136" srcset="https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2015/11/FedScoop50-484x220-300x136.jpg 300w, https://gsablogs.gsa.gov/innovation/files/2015/11/FedScoop50-484x220.jpg 484w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p>(Note: This blog post also appears at <a href="http://gsablogs.gsa.gov/gsablog/2015/11/20/gsa-leadership-named-to-2015-fedscoop-50/" target="_blank">The GSA Blog</a>.)</p>
<p>The federal technology community is taking notice of GSA’s drive to use technology to transform government as evident by awards given to four within GSA leadership.</p>
<p>GSA Administrator Denise Turner Roth, OCSIT Associate Administrator Phaedra Chrousos, Gwynne Kostin, Director of the OCSIT Digital Services Innovation Center, and GSA CIO David Shive were all recognized Nov. 19 as winners of the 2015 <a href="http://fedscoop.com/events/fedscoop50/">FedScoop 50 Awards</a></p>
<p>“The work behind receiving these awards was a true team effort,” said GSA Chief of Staff Katy Kale. “Everyone at GSA should be proud of their contributions putting technology to work for GSA and our agency customers.”</p>
<p>The Fedscoop 50 awards honor top leaders and achievements in the federal IT community.</p>
<p>Administrator Roth received the Golden Gov for being a visionary leader that implements innovative ideas, inspires others to get on board and has impact on not only their agency, but also the federal IT community and the country.</p>
<p>Part of the <a href="https://insite.gsa.gov/portal/content/689802">GSA vision</a> spearheaded by Roth is to <a href="https://insite.gsa.gov/portal/content/702486">help improve the federal government’s technology</a>. GSA’s role is becoming increasingly important as agencies look to technology to improve service, save money, and implement the Federal Information Technology Acquisition Reform Act (FITARA), a recent law that consolidates oversight of IT investments within agencies.</p>
<p>Chrousos received the Federal Leadership award for helping GSA implement new technologies, strategies and IT programs to lower the cost of government while making government more innovative, agile and effective.</p>
<p>Kostin received the Federal Leadership for delivering emerging technologies that better serve the American public and GSA’s customer agencies. Kostin’s team also released the Digital Analytics Dashboard, a tool that provides real time information on the U.S. government’s web traffic.</p>
<p>Shive won an award for his leadership in helping their GSA implement new technologies, strategies and IT programs to lower the cost of government while making government more innovative, agile and effective.</p>
<p>GSA is leading the way when it comes to providing the latest and most agile technology solutions to the federal government.</p>
<p>In addition, FAS and OCSIT teamed up to offer Connect.gov, a third-party sign-in partner providing a secure, privacy-enhancing service that conveniently connects people to government services and applications online, as a first step to providing government with the digital building blocks it needs to scale securely. Further, FAS, OGP, and GSA IT have partnered to improve cyber policies in government, provide access to necessary tools and procurements, and serve as thought leaders.</p>
<p>The award recipients received their honors at a ceremony on Nov. 19 only a couple blocks away from the White House in Washington, DC. The group reviewed more than 253,000 votes for thousands of nominees for this awards program.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>